Gustavo Sanchez

Automation & Data Science



Phone +91 766 5017 657

E-mail gustavo.sanchez@jklu.edu.in

ABOUT ME

25 years of experience as a consultant and researcher in Automation and Data Science. Successfully engineered and commissioned many projects in a wide variety of markets. 27 peer-reviewed published articles. In 2010, honored with the IEEE Computational Intelligence Society Best Paper Award. In 2015, invited by University of Maryland (USA) to give a course on Machine Learning applications to industrial problems. Expert in Python, R, MATLAB, C++, PLC and SCADA programming. Current research interest: Machine Learning, IoT and remote sensing applications.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- IoT, Data Science, Machine Learning, Remote Sensing applications
- Automation and networking solutions
- ISA automation standards
- Computational mathematical skills: optimization and simulation
- Expert in Neural Networks, Fuzzy Logic, Game Theory and Evolutionary Computation
- Design thinking for system modeling, simulation and integration
- Project-based and e-learning designer

EXPERIENCE

2018-2021 Professor JK Lakshmipat University, India

2015 Visiting Professor University of Maryland, USA

2000 – 2017 Professor Simon Bolivar University, Venezuela

1996 – 1999 Automation Engineer PDVSA, Venezuela. Automation of oil production facilities

Courses: Control Systems, Optimization, Operational Research, Machine Learning, Industrial Automation

EDUCATION

PhD in Science (2011)
Simon Bolivar University, Venezuela

BS in Ind. Systems Eng. (1996) University of Metz, France

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Ability to communicate in English, French and Spanish
- Interpersonal skills in international environments: work experience in Venezuela, France, Mexico, USA and India.
- Self-starter able to work with minimal supervision
- Open, creative and flexible.